[
    {
        "question": "A budget can be made by:",
        "option": [
            "keeping a diary of your expenses",
            "copying your friend’s budget.",
            " deciding what to buy when you go to the store.",
            "checking how much money is in your pocket"
        ],
        "answer": "keeping a diary of your expenses",
        "type": "budget making"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these is not a reason to budget?",
        "option": [
            "To put you in control of your money.",
            "To determine how much money you have to spend.",
            "To increase your income.",
            "To decrease your impulse spending."
        ],
        "answer": "To increase your income.",
        "type": "budget making"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which one of these is not part of a personal budget?",
        "option": [
            "Savings",
            "Giving to a church or charity",
            "Overspending",
            "Income"
        ],
        "answer": "Overspending",
        "type": "budget making"
    },
    {
        "question": "A budget helps you to",
        "option": [
            "buy everything you want",
            "balance your income with your expenses.",
            "overspend.",
            "earn more money."
        ],
        "answer": "balance your income with your expenses",
        "type": "budget making"
    },
    {
        "question": "Is budget helpful?",
        "option": [
            "sometime",
            "never",
            "always",
            "depend on your income "
        ],
        "answer": "always",
        "type": "budget making"
    },
    {
        "question": "Saving money means giving up the opportunity cost to",
        "option": [
            "apply for credit card",
            "spend in the present",
            "save money",
            "have money in future"
        ],
        "answer": "spend in the present",
        "type": "saving"
    },
    {
        "question": " Account payee cheques can be paid",
        "option": [
            "At cash counter of Bank",
            "At ATM",
            "By deposit in Bank account",
            "None of above"
        ],
        "answer": "By deposit in Bank account",
        "type": "banking"
    },
    {
        "question": "Bank provides loans for",
        "option": [
            "Home",
            "Car",
            "Education",
            "All of above"
        ],
        "answer": "All of above",
        "type": "banking"
    },
    {
        "question": "Bank does not give loan against",
        "option": [
            "Gold",
            "Home",
            "Lottery Ticket",
            "All of above"
        ],
        "answer": "Lottery Ticket",
        "type": "banking"
    },
    {
        "question": "Timely repayment of loans results",
        "option": [
            "Good reputations",
            "No tension",
            "Easily availability of loan in future",
            "All of above"
        ],
        "answer": "All of above",
        "type": "banking"
    },
    {
        "question": "You get a text message from a vendor who asks you to click on a link to renew your password so that you can log in to its website. You should:",
        "option": [
            " Reply to the text to confirm that you really need to renew your password.",
            "Click on the link. If it takes you to the vendor’s website, then you’ll know it’s not a scam.",
            "Pick up the phone and call the vendor, using a phone number you know to be correct, to confirm that the request is real.",
            "Avoid text"
        ],
        "answer": "Pick up the phone and call the vendor, using a phone number you know to be correct, to confirm that the request is real.",
        "type": "fraudery"
    },
    {
        "question": " If you fall for a phishing scam, what should you do to limit the damage?",
        "option": [
            "Delete the phishing email.",
            "Unplug the computer. This will get rid of any malware.",
            "none",
            "Change any compromised passwords."
        ],
        "answer": "Change any compromised passwords.",
        "type": "fraudery"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these businesses suffered the biggest data breach of all time, putting billions of its customers’ sensitive data at risk?",
        "option": [
            "Marriott International",
            "Yahoo.com",
            "Adult Friend Finder",
            "a dating site Equifax"
        ],
        "answer": "Yahoo.com",
        "type": "fraudery"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Federal Trade Commission (FTC) examined fraud reports in 2019 and found most often criminals first contacted victims by:",
        "option": [
            "calling them on phone",
            "Visiting them at their residence",
            "Sending an email",
            "Sending a letter in the mail"
        ],
        "answer": "calling them on phone",
        "type": "fraudery"
    },
    {
        "question": "Credit cards offer consumers better protection against liability for fraudulent purchases compared with debit cards because of the:",
        "option": [
            "Electronic Fund Transfer Act",
            "Federal Reserve Bank’s Regulation E",
            "Fair Credit Billing Act",
            "none"
        ],
        "answer": "Fair Credit Billing Act",
        "type": "fraudery"
    },
    {
        "question": "Money is a Medium of",
        "option": [
            "communication",
            "exchange",
            "barter",
            "spectulations "
        ],
        "answer": "exchange",
        "type": "money"
    },
    {
        "question": " Money contains:",
        "option": [
            "coins",
            "cheque",
            "currency notes",
            "All of above"
        ],
        "answer": "All of above",
        "type": "money"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the monetary authority in India?",
        "option": [
            "RBI",
            "Cetral bank",
            "Ministry of Finance",
            "cabinet"
        ],
        "answer": "RBI",
        "type": "money"
    },
    {
        "question": "What solves the problem of double coincidence of wants?",
        "option": [
            "Goods",
            "Banks",
            "Money",
            "All of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "Money",
        "type": "money"
    },
    {
        "question": "Money helps man to …………….. his wants",
        "option": [
            "multiply",
            "satisfy",
            "create",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "satisfy",
        "type": "money"
    },
    {
        "question": "Savings is directly connected with ……………….",
        "option": [
            "consumption",
            "production",
            "investment",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "investment",
        "type": "money"
    },
    {
        "question": " What does it mean to have a negative savings rate?",
        "option": [
            "spending more money than you make and acquiring debt.",
            "no saving",
            "huge amount of saving",
            "All of above"
        ],
        "answer": "spending more money than you make and acquiring debt.",
        "type": "money"
    },
    {
        "question": "For which of the following should you save?",
        "option": [
            "emergency",
            "wealth building",
            "purchase",
            "All of above"
        ],
        "answer": "All of above",
        "type": "money"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these is NOT a key to saving money?",
        "option": [
            "Making Saving Habit",
            "Focus",
            "Income",
            "Discipline"
        ],
        "answer": "Income",
        "type": "money"
    },
    {
        "question": "Interest paid on interest previously earned",
        "option": [
            "simple interest",
            "compound interest",
            "Both of A & B ",
            "none"
        ],
        "answer": "compound interest",
        "type": "money"
    }
]